## **SHORT BIOGRAPHY**

I am a 4th year PhD student in Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science & Engineering at the University of Washington, recently moved from Robotics Institute at Carnegie Mellon University, with my advisor, Siddhartha S. Srinivasa. I received B.S. and M.Eng at MIT, where I was co-advised by Leslie P. Kaelbling and Tomas Lozano-Perez. I am a recipient of Kwanjeong Educational Foundation Fellowship and have previously received CMU School of Computer Science Presidential Fellowship and Samsung Scholarship.

My primary research interest is to enable robots to acquire diverse manipulation skills and to interact with humans so that they can assist humans in uncertain and cluttered environments such as the home. More broadly, I am interested in domain adaptation for model-based reinforcement learning and machine learning with physics-based priors. I have worked on a variety of problems in robotics and computer graphics. In robotics, I worked on multi-contact nonprehensile manipulation, multi-step planning, and SLAM-based object pose estimation. In computer graphics, I worked on skin deformation and lighting for 3D animation.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Washington**

Seattle, WA

Ph.D. Student in Computer Science Advisor: Siddhartha S. Srinivasa Jan. 2018 - June 2021 (expected)

# Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

M.S. in Robotics Institute, School of Computer Science

Sep. 2015 - May 2017

Advisor: Matthew T. Mason, Siddhartha S. Srinivasa

Thesis: GP-ILQG: Data-driven Robust Optimal Control for Uncertain Nonlinear Dynamical Systems

#### Massachusetts Institute of Technology (GPA: 5.0 / 5.0)

Cambridge, MA

M.Eng. in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

June 2015

Advisor: Leslie P. Kaelbling, Tomás Lozano-Peréz

Thesis: Hierarchical planning for multi-contact non-prehensile manipulation

#### Massachusetts Institute of Technology (GPA: 4.7 / 5.0)

Cambridge, MA

B.S. in EECS and Mathematics

June 2010

# **AWARDS & HONORS**

#### **Kwanjeong Educational Foundation Fellowship**

2015 - Present

#### **CMU School of Computer Science Presidential Fellowship**

2016 - 2017

**IROS Best Paper Finalist**, Hierarchical planning for multi-contact non-prehensile manipulation

2015

Samsung Scholarship, one of ten undergraduate awardees

2006 - 2010

## RESEARCH

#### Personal Robotics Lab

CMU RI, Univ. of Washington

**Research Associate** 

Sep. 2015 – Present

- Developed algorithms for model-based reinforcement learning for robust control of robots under uncertainty
- Developed and maintained a multistep planning framework for manipulation

#### **Oculus Research Pittsburgh**

Oculus

Ph.D. Intern

May 2017 – Dec. 2017

• Worked on research problems related to human motion prediction in social settings

#### **Learning and Intelligent Systems Group**

MIT CSAIL

Research Associate

Jan. 2014 – June 2015

• Developed a planning algorithm for multi-contact nonprehensile object manipulation

#### **MIT DARPA Robotics Challenge Team**

MIT CSAIL

Research Associate

Jan. - June 2014

• Extended Parallel Tracking and Mapping algorithm for object pose estimation and tracking in pre-grasping stage

#### **Walt Disney Animation Studios**

Research Associate, Animation Technology Research Team

Burbank, CA Jan 2010

• Implemented and analyzed a heat-based skin attachment algorithm and compared it against skeleton-subspace-deformation method

Canon Tokyo, Japan

Research Associate, Visual Information Processing Technology Development Center

- June Dec. 2008
- Designed an interactive photoframe that learns user's facial expressions to display photos evoking positive reaction
- Collaborated with Waseda University for predicting future demand for monitoring systems in senior care industry

## INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL PUBLICATION

Bhattacharjee, B., Lee, G., Song, H., and Srinivasa. S.S. Towards Robotic Feeding: Role of Haptics in Fork-based Food Manipulation., *IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (IEEE RA-L).* 2019.

#### INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE PUBLICATION

Lee, G., Deng, Z., Ma, S., and Shiratori, T. and Srinivasa, S.S. and Sheikh, Y. Talking With Hands 16.2M: A Large-Scale Dataset of Synchronized Body-Finger Motion and Audio for Conversational Motion Analysis and Synthesis, *In IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*. 2019.

Lee, G., Feng, R., Kim, Y., Gordon, E.K., Schmittle, M., Kumar, S., Bhattacharjee, T., Srinivasa, S.S. Robot-Assisted Feeding: Generalizing Skewering Strategies across Food Items on a Plate. In *International Symposium on Robotics Research (ISRR)*. 2019.

Lee, G., Hou, B., Mandalika, A., Lee, J., Choudhury, S., and Srinivasa, S.S. Bayesian Policy Optimization for Model Uncertainty, *In International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)*. 2019.

Sheikholeslami, S., Lee, G., Hart, J.W., Srinivasa, S.S., and Croft. E.A. A Study of Reaching Motions for Collaborative Human-Robot Interaction, In *International Symposium on Experimental Robotics (ISER)*. 2018.

Srinivasa, S., Lee, G., et. al. A System for Multi-Step Mobile Manipulation: Architecture, Algorithms, and Experiments, *International Symposium on Experimental Robotics (ISER)*, 2016.

Lee, G., Kaelbling, L., and Lozano-Perez, T. Hierarchical planning for multi-contact non-prehensile manipulation, *IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)*, 2015. [Best Conference Paper Finalist]

#### **PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES**

Panel, RSS 2019 Workshop on Closing the Reality Gap in Sim2real Transfer for Robotic Manipulation

Panel, IEEE/RSJ IROS 2017 Workshop on Development of Benchmarking Protocols for Robot Manipulation

Organizer, RSS 2017 Workshop on (Empirically) Data-Driven Manipulation

Reviewer, IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and System (IROS)

Reviewer, IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)

Reviewer, Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)

Reviewer, International Journal of Robotics Research (IJRR)

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Mobile Robots
Teaching Assistant
UW CSE
Spring 2017

• Managed grades and assignments for students; assisted in lesson planning, mentored group projects; led recitations

Robot Autonomy CMU Robotics Institute

Teaching Assistant Spring 2017

• Managed grades and assignments for students; assisted in lesson planning, mentored group projects; led recitations

Software Construction MIT EECS

**Teaching Assistant** 

Spring & Fall 2014, Spring 2015

• Managed grades and assignments for students; assisted in lesson planning, mentored group projects; led recitations

# **PROGRAMMING SKILLS**

Extensive experience in C++, Python, MATLAB, and Java.

# **VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES**

# **Undergraduate Student Advisory Group in EECS (USAGE)**Member

Cambridge, MA 2014 – 2015

• Advised for curriculum changes and getting more entrepreneurial opportunities for EECS undergraduates

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

GIST Sunnyvale, CA

#### Co-founder, Lead Developer

2013

- Designed an algorithm that crawls news and extracts key contents through Natural Language Processing
- Led the development team for mobile application development
- Raised seed funding through Plug and Play Tech Center's incubator program

#### **Michigan Venture Capital**

Seoul, Korea

2012

Analyst, Investment Team

- Managed three media-focused funds, each valued at 10M 15M USD
- Supervised opening of *Ultra Music Festival Korea*, held at the national stadium in Korea.
- Supervised three film productions for casting, production schedule, distributor contracts; broke advance sales record

#### **DreamWorks Animation SKG**

Glendale, CA

Technical Director, Kung Fu Panda 2 Production Team

July 2010 - June 2011

- Developed and assisted in production pipeline
- Tested new in-house lighting algorithms and management tools
- Resolved technical issues for lighting artists and optimized rendering process on a daily basis